<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mina Attia</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mina Attia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/resume/</guid>
      <description>My name is Mina Attia and I was born in Alexandria, Egypt. At age 11, I immigrated to the US and have been residing in Texas. My edcuational background is concentrated in the biological sciences and business. My interests include medicine, entrepreneurship, and politics. My work experience includes pharmacokinetics research, phlebotomy, and retail. My skills range from being trilingual (Arabic, English, French) to my ability to teamwork effectively. Some of my accomplishments include research and educational awards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio and Python</title>
      <link>/blog/rstudio-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rstudio-and-python/</guid>
      <description>In SDS 348, I have used RStudio to analyze a dataset that contained information about lung cancer patients who were veterans.
The last unit of the class explored Python, a commonly used programming language. I personally really like Python because it is very user friendly and allowed me to gain practical skills in the realm of programming. Python can do many things, including constructing plots and figures. For example, examine the figure below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have been working on:
  Project 1
  Project 2
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis - Mina Attia</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I chose to work with these two datasets, veteran and cancer, since they are both related to lung cancer, which is a sector of medicine that interests me. The veteran dataset consists of randomized trial for veterans that explores two types of treatment for lung cancer. It contains variables such as cancer cell type, survival time, karno score (higher = better overall health), diagnosis time, age, and prior therapy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I chose to work with the veteran dataset since it relates to lung cancer, which is a sector of medicine that interests me. The dataset is the Veterans’ Administrations Lung Cancer study and consists of randomized trial for veterans that explores two types of treatment for lung cancer. It contains variables such as cancer cell type, survival time, karno score (higher = better overall health), diagnosis time, age, and prior therapy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>